



© Contact

□Email: ammarhanyezeldin@gmail.com

**Phone:**+46 739 793 588

+90 539 577 59 90

+20 106 188 84 76

■Websites
■Website

□LinkedIn
○GitHub

Experienced Computer and Software Engineer with an interest in AI, Computer Vision, and Backend, specializing in AI, Computer Vision, Backend, and IoT. Proficient in Python and C#. I have over 3 years of experience. Currently seeking full-time opportunities in Software Engineering Roles, I am open to remote, hybrid, or on-site positions with relocation availability.

Skills	
Programming Languages	C#, Python, C++, Java, PHP, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, SQL, XAML
Frontend Frameworks	Bootstrap
Backend Frameworks	Flask, ASP.NET, Entity Framework, MVC, Razor, Blazor, Laravel, .NET, REST API, JSON, YAML, .ENV, Node.js, Spring Boo
Desktop Frameworks	WPF
Database Technologies	MySQL, MSSQL, SQLite, Firebase, Postgres
Mobile Frameworks	Android
Al Frameworks	TensorFlow, Keras, PyTorch, OpenCV, Ultralytics, Supervision, YOLO
Python Libraries	NumPy, Pandas, OS, Shutil, JWT, Gunicorn, PIL, glob, hashlib, google.cloud
Cloud Services	Google Cloud Platform
DevOps Tools	Docker, Artifact Registry
Applications and Tools	VSCode, Visual Studio, PyCharm, Android Studio, IntelliJ, Wix, Fl Studio, Microsoft 365 (Office), Microsoft Word, Excel, Power Point, CMake, Postman, SSH, VM
Fields and Technologies	Full-Stack, AI, Mobile Development, Web Development, Database Management, DevOps, REST Apis, Backend Development, Machine Learning, Deep Learning, Version Control, Cloud Computing, Game Industry
Languages	English (C2), Turkish (B2), Arabic (Native), Swedish (A1), French (A1)
Skills	Quick Learner, Attention to Detail, <b>Problem Solving</b> , Creativity, Teamwork, Mentorship, Leadership, Fast typer

# **Work Experience**

#### Mid-Level Software Engineer | Animals Animals.Al

Helsingborg, Sweden | 08/2023 - 04/2024

- Developed 30+ advanced Computer Vision Models and 50+ image processing algorithms.
- Managed annotation tasks for over 10,000 images.
- Automated model training using Google Compute Engine, including automatic data downloading, training, and model deployment.
- Managed backend infrastructure on Google Cloud Platform, overseeing Firebase and Cloud Run for storage systems.
- Designed and optimized REST APIs, facilitating team efficiency.
- Composed an automated camera system with up to 12 cameras for AI scripts and IoT solutions.
- Worked with 5+ Nvidia Jetson devices on one network, leveraging RTSP technologies.
- Mentored 3+ interns in API development, backend engineering, and computer vision techniques.
- Acquired extensive knowledge of agriculture practices through IoT work, 5+ farm visits, and collaboration with 4+ researchers and engineers.

#### Internship in IT | Toros University

Mersin, Turkey | 03/2023 - 07/2023

- Maintained the company's IT infrastructure. Fixed about 50% of the laboratory's computers.
- Ensured that they were prepared for use by thousands of students.
- Assisted the professors with all their technical problems with a 100% satisfaction rate.

# Internship in IT | Toros University

Mersin, Turkey | 07/2022 - 09/2022

Gained experience in a variety of IT tasks, including software development, system administration, and network engineering.

## Freelance | Full Stack Web Development

Mersin, Turkey | 09/2021 - 09/2022

- Able to work independently to meet deadlines and deliver projects on time and within budget.
- Collaborated with marketing agencies for developing their websites while including SEO.

# **Education**

#### Toros University | Bachelor of Computer and Software Engineering

Mersin, Turkey | 09/2019 - 07/2023

- Ranked 1<sup>st</sup> Student on Computer and software Engineering Department and Engineering Faculty and Ranked 2<sup>nd</sup> on the whole University.
- GPA: 3.77/4.00. Passed all semesters with honors. (Transcript)
- Member of administrative board in Computer Sciences Community
- Graduation Project: Behaviour Cloning Self Driving Car
- Top Projects: Web Crawler, Inventory Management System, Library Management System, Cashier Application, Forums Web Application

#### **Additional Courses**

 Online Courses: ASP.NET, Full Stack Web Development, Laravel, C#, Java, Python, Android, Fl Studio, Learning, Self-Driving Car, Data Structure, Algorithms, JavaScript, WordPress, Pytorch, Spring, Spring Boot

# Certificates

## Al Engineer Internship Certificate | Animals.ai (Link)

Helsingborg, Sweden | 08/2023 - 10/2023

- Completed an intensive internship program at Animals.Al, where I demonstrated exceptional initiative and problem-solving skills.
- Successfully completed a computer vision Al project originally scheduled for 3 months in just 2 weeks.
- Introduced and implemented an innovative approach to a project, resulting in improved efficiency and project outcomes adopted by the company.

## Lead Al Engineer Smart Lab | Toros University (Link)

Mersin, Turkey | Teknofest 2023

 Built backend system with a GPU-accelerated computer vision model to detect selected fruits for Autonomous Harvesting robot and get their coordinates. Teknofest Contest Was attended by 2.5 million visitors. Ranked 25th.

#### Certificate Of Completion | Udemy (Link)

Mersin, Turkey | 29.01.2023

• The Complete Self-Driving Car Course – Applied Deep Learning